Register to The Karl Weigl Papers
Yale University Music Library
- Correspondence, Series II
  - Welch, Sylvia Spencer, 1932-1934; 5 items. (Box 25, Folder 801)
  - Wellesley College
    See Smaill, Edith M.
  - Whitney, George Gillett, 1943 May 15; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 802)
  - Wiefler, Florian, 1947-1948; 2 items. (Box 25, Folder 803)
  - Wiener Humanitäre Schreibstube, 1927 Apr. 29; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 804)
  - William C. Whitney Foundation, 1945 Aug. 27; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 805)
  - Winkelmann, Hermann, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 806)
  - Wittgenstein, Paul, 1932 Feb. 22; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 807)
  - Woodruff, Edith S., 1938 Jun. 14; 1 item. (Box 25, Folder 808)
  - Yale University, 1938 Jul.-Aug.; 2 items. (Box 25, Folder 809)
  - Younker, Mrs. Ira M., 1937-1938; 3 items. (Box 25, Folder 810)
  - Zemlinsky, Alexander, 1902-1934, n.d.; 8 items. (Box 25, Folder 811)
    Includes postcard with unidentified signatures
  - -----, Marjorie
    See Cooper, Elizabeth M.
  - Unidentified, 1902-1948, n.d.; 39 items. (Box 25, Folder 812-815)
    Includes photograph of Weigl, Vally Weigl, and unidentified
- Writings, Series III
  This series consists of a small amount of materials organized into two subseries: Lectures, mostly concerning music history and music appreciation; and Other Writings, consisting of Weigl's dissertation, "Emanuel Aloys Förster," and an article titled "Erinnerungen an Gustav Mahler," in German and English translation. Both subseries are arranged alphabetically by title.
  - Lectures, III.A
    - "Appreciation of Music", n.d.; typescript (Box 25, Folder 816)
    - "Introduction into [sic] Music Theory", n.d.; typescript (Box 25, Folder 817)
    - "On the Teaching of Music Appreciation", n.d.; typescript (Box 25, Folder 818)
    - "Opera", n.d.; holograph (Box 25, Folder 819)
    - "Symphony", n.d.; holograph (Box 25, Folder 820)
    - "Understanding the Symphonies", holograph (Box 25, Folder 821)
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 822)
  - Other Writings, III.B
    - "Emanuel Aloys Förster," dissertation, University of Vienna, Sammelbände der Internationalen Musikgesellschaft, [1903] (Box 25, Folder 823)
    - "Erinnerungen an Gustav Mahler," article, 1947, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 824)
      Typescripts in German and English translation and article in Austria
    - "Erinnerungen an Gustav Mahler," English translation in Musical Courier, 1948 (Box 31, Folder 1042)
- Biographical Material, Series IV
  This series consists chiefly of clippings about Weigl and printed pamphlets containing curriculum vitae, works lists, and excerpts from reviews and testimonials. Some clippings and pamphlets date from after Weigl's death; also present are obituary clippings, lists of works prepared by publishers or Vally Weigl, a list of performances of Weigl's works, 1960-1970, and reminiscences written by Maria Weigl Piers and Kurt Adler. This series is arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Biographical pamphlets, [ca. 1911-ca. 1970] (Box 26, Folder 825)
  - Clippings, 1931-1937, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 826)
  - Clippings, 1947 (Box 26, Folder 827)
  - Clippings, 1950-1981, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 828)
  - Curriculum vitae and lists of works, [after 1939] (Box 26, Folder 829)
  - "The Music of Karl Weigl (1881-1949): A Catalog," edited by Stephen Davison (Jay K. Hoffman and Associates), [198-?] (Box 26, Folder 830)
  - Obituaries, 1949 (Box 26, Folder 831)
  - "Performances and Publications of Karl Weigl's Music Between 1960-1970" (Box 26, Folder 832)
  - Publishers' works lists, 1977, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 833-834)
  - Reminiscences about Weigl, 1949-1979 (Box 26, Folder 835)
- Programs and Publicity, Series V
  This series, arranged chronologically, contains printed programs for performances of Weigl's music and other publicity materials, such as drafts of programs, press announcements, tickets, radio program publicity and radio announcement scripts, and invitations and programs for private concerts.
  - Programs and publicity, 1900-1909 (Box 26, Folder 836)
  - Programs and publicity, 1910 (Box 26, Folder 837-838)
  - Programs and publicity, 1911-1919 (Box 26, Folder 839)
  - Programs and publicity, 1920-1929 (Box 26, Folder 840)
  - Programs and publicity, 1930-1938 (Box 26, Folder 841)
  - Programs and publicity, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 842)
  - Programs and publicity, n.d. [before 1939] (Box 26, Folder 843)
  - Programs and publicity, n.d. [before 1939] (Box 31, Folder 1043)
  - Programs and publicity, 1940-1941 (Box 26, Folder 844)
  - Programs and publicity, 1942 (Box 26, Folder 845)
  - Programs and publicity, 1943-1944 (Box 26, Folder 846)
  - Programs and publicity, 1945-1949 (Box 27, Folder 847)
  - Programs and publicity, 1950-1952 (Box 27, Folder 848)
  - Programs and publicity, 1953-1959 (Box 27, Folder 849)
  - Programs and publicity, 1960-1966 (Box 27, Folder 850)
  - Programs and publicity, 1967-1969 (Box 27, Folder 851)
  - Programs and publicity, 1970-1979 (Box 27, Folder 852)
  - Programs and publicity, 1980-1982 (Box 27, Folder 853)
  - Programs and publicity, n.d. [after 1939] (Box 27, Folder 854-856)
- Reviews, Series VI
  This series consists of two subseries, each arranged chronologically: Clippings and Transcriptions; and Annotated Envelopes. Many reviews dating from Weigl's years in Vienna were obtained from clippings services; also present are other clippings and typed transcripts of single reviews or sets of reviews. Some reviews were previously housed in envelopes and organized roughly by work. These envelopes, some with annotations about performances, are now filed separately in the second subseries.
  - Clippings and Transcriptions, VI.A
    - Reviews, 1901 (Box 27, Folder 857)
    - Reviews, 1902-1906 (Box 27, Folder 858)
    - Reviews, 1907-1909 (Box 27, Folder 859)
    - Reviews, 1910 Jan.-Jun. (Box 27, Folder 860)
    - Reviews, 1910 Jul.-Dec. (Box 27, Folder 861)
    - Reviews, 1911-1912 (Box 27, Folder 862)
    - Reviews, 1913 (Box 27, Folder 863)
    - Reviews, 1914 (Box 27, Folder 864)
    - Reviews, 1915-1918 (Box 27, Folder 865)
    - Reviews, 1919 (Box 27, Folder 866)
    - Sets of transcriptions, 1920-1929 (Box 27, Folder 867)
    - Sets of transcriptions, 1920-1939 (Box 27, Folder 868)
    - Reviews, 1920 (Box 27, Folder 869)
    - Reviews, 1921 (Box 27, Folder 870)
    - Reviews, 1922 (Box 27, Folder 871)
    - Reviews, 1923 (Box 27, Folder 872)
    - Reviews, 1924 (Box 27, Folder 873)
    - Reviews, 1925 (Box 27, Folder 874)
    - Reviews, 1926 (Box 27, Folder 875)
    - Reviews, 1927 (Box 27, Folder 876)
    - Reviews, 1928 (Box 27, Folder 877)
    - Reviews, 1929 (Box 27, Folder 878)
    - Sets of transcriptions, 1930 (Box 27, Folder 879)
    - Sets of transcriptions, 1930-1939 (Box 28, Folder 880)
    - Sets of reviews, 1930s-1970s (Box 28, Folder 881)
    - Sets of reviews, 1930s-1970s (Box 31, Folder 1044)
    - Reviews, 1930 (Box 28, Folder 882)
    - Reviews, 1930 (Box 31, Folder 1045)
    - Reviews, 1931 (Box 28, Folder 883)
    - Reviews, 1932-1933 (Box 28, Folder 884)
    - Reviews, 1934 (Box 28, Folder 885)
    - Reviews, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 886)
    - Reviews, 1936 (Box 28, Folder 887)
    - Reviews, 1937 (Box 28, Folder 888)
    - Reviews, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 889)
    - Reviews, 1939 (Box 28, Folder 890)
    - Reviews, n.d. [before 1939] (Box 28, Folder 891)
    - Reviews, 1940-1949 (Box 28, Folder 892)
    - Reviews, 1950-1959 (Box 28, Folder 893)
    - Reviews, 1960-1969 (Box 28, Folder 894)
    - Reviews, 1970-1979 (Box 28, Folder 895)
    - Reviews, 1980-1982 (Box 28, Folder 896)
    - Reviews, n.d. [after 1939] (Box 28, Folder 897)
  - Annotated Envelopes, VI.B
    - Envelopes, 1902-1919 (Box 28, Folder 898)
    - Envelopes, 1920-1929 (Box 28, Folder 899)
    - Envelopes, 1930-1956 (Box 28, Folder 900)
    - Envelopes, n.d. (Box 28, Folder 901)
- Photographs, Series VII
  This series consists of three subseries: Karl Weigl Alone, Karl Weigl With Other People, and Other People. Photographs of Weigl alone include portraits and snapshots dating from his early career in Vienna to shortly before his death. Also in this subseries is a small group of photographs of Karl, Vally, and John Weigl originally housed in a small portfolio. The second subseries, Karl Weigl With Other People, includes additional photographs of Vally and John Weigl; a photograph of composers at the Salzburger Festspiele, 1922 or 1923, including Weigl, Paul Hindemith, Anton Webern; and other photographs of Weigl with unidentified musicians. The third subseries, Other People, includes a photograph of Johannes Brahms with an unidentified man; photographs of Gustav Mahler; and a photograph of Paul Hindemith, members of the Amar-Quartett, and Erika Stiedry-Wagner following a performance of Weigl's Stelldichein at the Salzburger Festspiele, 1922. Reproductions of additional photographs of Karl Weigl may be found in clippings and pamphlets in Series IV, Biographical Material.
  - Karl Weigl Alone, VII.A
    See also Biographical Material
    - Weigl, Karl, 1916-ca. 1949; items 1-5. (Box 28, Folder 902)
    - Weigl, Karl, n.d.; items 6-15. (Box 28, Folder 903-904)
    - Portfolio with photographs of Weigl and Weigl with John and Vally Weigl, 1918, n.d.; items 16-21. (Box 28, Folder 905)
  - Karl Weigl With Other People, VII.B
    - Weigl; Alwin, Karl; Grosz, Wilhelm; Bliss, Arthur; Hindemith, Paul; Reti, Rudolph; Smyth, Ethel; Pisk, Paul Amadeus; Pijper, Willem; Lustgarten, Egon; Wellesz, Egon; Webern, Anton; Horwitz, Karl; and Kauder, Hugo (Salzburger Festspiele), [1922 Aug]; item 22. (Box 28, Folder 906)
    - Weigl, John, n.d.; items 23-24. (Box 28, Folder 907)
    - Weigl, John; Weigl, Vally; unidentified, n.d.; item 25. (Box 28, Folder 908)
    - Weigl, Vally, n.d.; item 26. (Box 28, Folder 909)
    - Weigl, Vally; unidentified, n.d.; items 27-29. (Box 28, Folder 910)
      See also photograph enclosed in Karl Weigl Correspondence / Unidentified
    - Unidentified at Berchtesgaden, Germany, 1918; items 30-32. (Box 28, Folder 911)
    - Unidentified violinist, n.d.; item 33. (Box 29, Folder 912)
    - Unidentified singer, n.d.; items 34-39. (Box 29, Folder 913)
      With portfolio
    - Unidentified, n.d.; items 40-45. (Box 29, Folder 914)
  - Other people, VII.C
    - Brahms, Johannes; unidentified, [1894?]; item 46. (Box 29, Folder 915)
    - Gieseking, Walter; Stiedry-Wagner, Erika; Amar-Quartett (Frank, Maurits; Hindemith, Paul; Amar, Licco; Caspar, Walter) ("after performing Karl Weigl's Stelldichein," Salzburger Festspiele), [1922 Aug]; item 47. (Box 29, Folder 916)
    - Harris, Hilda, item 48. (Box 29, Folder 917)
    - Mahler, Gustav, n.d.; items 49-51. (Box 29, Folder 918)
    - New World String Quartet, item 52. (Box 29, Folder 919)
    - Lucy Shelton, item 53. (Box 29, Folder 920)
    - George Shirley, item 54. (Box 29, Folder 921)
    - Siegel, Rudolf, item 54. (Box 29, Folder 921)
      See Siegel, Rudolf, in Correspondence Series
    - Silverthorne, Paul, item 55. (Box 29, Folder 922)
    - Weigl, Vally, n.d.; item 55a. (Box 29, Folder 922a)
    - Unidentified, 1931-1951, n.d.; items 56-60. (Box 29, Folder 923)
      With photograph developer's envelope
- Other Papers, Series VIII
  This series, arranged alphabetically by type of material, includes a diary with brief entries for 1934-1938, an early notebook of poems copied by Weigl, and items dating from his years in the United States, including teaching contracts, address books, records of students, and lists of music loaned to musicians.
  - Address books and lists, [after 1939] (Box 29, Folder 924-925)
  - Diary, 1934-1938 (Box 29, Folder 926)
  - Notebook of poems copied by Weigl, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 927)
  - Records of music loaned to musicians (notebook and lists), 1940-1951, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 928-929)
  - Records of students and other notes (notebook and lists), 1939-1948, n.d. (Box 29, Folder 930-931)
  - Teaching contracts, 1940-1945 (Box 29, Folder 932)
- Vally Weigl Papers, Series IX
  This series consists of three subseries: Correspondence, Karl Weigl Memorial Fund, and Other Papers. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by name, with incoming and outgoing letters interfiled. All correspondence in this series dates from after Karl's death. A small amount of earlier correspondence of Vally is present is Karl Weigl's Correspondence (Series II); correspondents appearing in both series are cross referenced. Many letters in this series relate to the Karl Weigl Memorial Fund, including solicitations of initial support in 1966, subsequent appeals for donations, and establishment of other performance and recording funds. Other letters concern additional efforts to promote Karl Weigl's music and the disposition of his music manuscripts and other papers. Also present are letters concerning Vally Weigl's music, her later life, and the Weigl family. Correspondents include Kurt Adler, Ernst Bacon, Pablo Casals, Sam Denison, Ira Arthur Hirschmann, Hans Moldenhauer, Maria Weigl Piers, Daniel Sternberg, Jean Starr Untermeyer, Ruth T. Watanabe, John Weigl, and Florian Wiefler.
  The second subseries, Karl Weigl Memorial Fund, consists of financial records, lists of contributors, and records of expenses documenting Vally Weigl's involvement with administration of the Fund at the Mannes College of Music and Indiana University. Materials are arranged alphabetically by type of material. Additional material concerning the Karl Weigl Memorial Fund is in Vally Weigl's correspondence.
  The third subseries, Other Papers, includes biographical material about Vally Weigl and material relating to establishment of her performance and recording fund at the College of Charleston, an article by her titled "Functional Music With Cerebral Palsied Children," and papers relating to Karl Weigl's death and disposition of his papers.
  - Correspondence, IX.A
    - Acks, Harold, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 29, Folder 933)
    - Adler, Kurt, 1952-1970; 4 items. (Box 29, Folder 934)
    - American Composers Alliance
      See Smyth, Christina
      See also Karl Weigl Correspondence
    - Arsis Press, 1980 Mar. 8; 1 item. (Box 29, Folder 935)
    - Aspen Music Festival
      See Hardy, Gordon
    - AUFBAU (New York), 1956 Mar. 5; 1 item. (Box 29, Folder 936)
      See also Breuer, Robert
    - Bacon, Ernst, 1966 Feb.; 2 items. (Box 29, Folder 937)
    - Barolin, M.
      See Stadelmann, Egon
    - Baylor University
      See Sternberg, Daniel
    - Bean, Calvert, 1966 Apr.-May; 2 items. (Box 29, Folder 938)
    - Braunstein, Joseph, 1979-1981; 3 items. (Box 29, Folder 939)
    - Breuer, Robert, 1966 Feb. 14; 1 item. (Box 29, Folder 940)
    - Campbell, Frank, 1977 Dec. 20; 1 item. (Box 29, Folder 941)
    - Carnegie Hall
      See Warkow, Stewart J.
    - Casals, Pablo, 1952-1956; 2 items. (Box 29, Folder 942)
      Photocopies
    - Castle, William B., 1949 Jul.-Aug.; 2 items. (Box 29, Folder 943)
    - Coggins, Miss, 1976 Apr. 21; 1 item. (Box 29, Folder 944)
    - Community Trust Fund (New York), 1965 Nov. 2; 1 item. (Box 29, Folder 945)
    - Composers Recordings, Inc., [1981?]; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 946)
    - Cornfield, George, 1980 Feb. 14; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 947)
    - Dennison, Sam, 1978-1980; 6 items. (Box 30, Folder 948)
    - De Paur, Leonard, 1980 Feb. 5; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 949)
    - Eastman School of Music
      See Freeman, Robert; Watanabe, Ruth T.
    - Edwin A. Fleisher Collection of Orchestral Music
      See Dennison, Sam
    - Frankenstein, Dr., 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 950)
    - Freeman, Robert, 1978-1980; 4 items. (Box 30, Folder 951)
    - Fuchs, Peter Paul, 1966 Feb. 5; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 952)
    - Gamsjäher, Rudolf, 1969 Mar. 11; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 953)
    - Gelber, Sidney, 1965 Dec.; 2 items. (Box 30, Folder 954)
    - General Music Publishing Company
      See Kapp, Paul
    - Gesellschaft der Musikfreunde in Wien
      See Gamsjäher, Rudolf
    - Goethe House
      See Marx, Henry
    - Goldberg, Szymon, 1966 Jan. 30; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 955)
    - Gressler, Gene M.
      See University of Wyoming. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections
    - Guarneri Quartet, 1966 Jan. 30; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 956)
    - Halász, László, 1966 Jan. 20; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 957)
    - Hardy, Gordon, 1978 Jun. 12; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 958)
    - Harth, Sidney, 1966 Jan. 19; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 959)
    - Hauser, Arthur, 1966 Jan. 30; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 960)
    - Hendl, Walter, 1967 Oct. 27; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 961)
    - Hirschmann, Ira Arthur, 1965-1967; 8 items. (Box 30, Folder 962)
      See also Untermeyer, Jean Starr; Yarnall, Elizabeth
    - Indiana University School of Music
      See Webb, Charles
    - Institute for Studies in American Music, 1978 Nov. 8; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 963)
    - Interracial Chorus (Broadway Tabernacle) (New York)
      See Acks, Harold
    - Kalmus, Alfred, 1966 Mar. 30; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 964)
    - Kaplan, Abraham, 1966 Feb.; 2 items. (Box 30, Folder 965)
    - Kapp, Paul, 1980 Feb. 29; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 966)
      To John Weigl
    - Karl Weigl Memorial Fund, 1971; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 967)
      See also Adler, Kurt; Coggins, Miss; Gelber, Sidney; Hirschmann, Ira; McGinn, M. John; Moon, Eugene; Waldman, Frederic
    - Karl Weigl Performance and Recording Award Fund
      See Freeman, Robert
    - Kozma, Tibor, 1966 Jan. 19; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 968)
    - Litschauer, Franz, 1966 Sep. 14; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 969)
    - Loewenguth, Alfred, 1966-1967; 2 items. (Box 30, Folder 970)
    - Lorr, [Mrs. Ralph], 1966 Nov. 17; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 971)
    - McGinn, M. John, 1969-1972; 12 items. (Box 30, Folder 972)
    - Malucelli, Kenneth, 1982 Jul. 7; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 973)
    - Mannes College of Music
      See Gelber, Sidney
    - Marx, Henry, 1978 Sep. 17; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 974)
    - Maves, David, 1980 Jan. 7; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 975)
      See also Vally Weigl Performance and Recording Fund (in Other Papers)
    - Menuhin, Yehudi, 1966 Jan. 29; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 976)
    - Miller, Philip L., 1965 Nov. 8; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 977)
    - Moldenhauer, Hans, 1967-1982; 2 items. (Box 30, Folder 978)
    - Moon, Eugene, 1969-1972; 13 items. (Box 30, Folder 979)
    - Moore, David, [ca. 1980]; 4 items. (Box 30, Folder 980)
    - Mousel, Donald K., 1982 Feb. 12; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 981)
    - New York Public Library
      See Campbell, Frank; Miller, Philip L.
    - New Yorker Staats-Zeitung und Herold
    - Orion Master Recordings
      See Cornfield, George
    - Piers, Gerhart
    - Piers, Maria Weigl, 1950-1966, n.d.; 20 items. (Box 30, Folder 982)
      See also Waldman, Frederic; Karl Weigl Correspondence
    - Riemann Musiklexikon, 1960 Jul.; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 983)
    - Roy, Klaus George
      See Music by Others
    - Shirley, George, 1972 Feb. 3; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 984)
    - Silvermine Guild Chamber Music Center, 1968 Sep. 26; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 985)
    - Sincock, Harold R., 1970 Aug. 19; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 986)
    - Smyth, Christina, 1980 Feb. 20; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 987)
      From John Weigl
    - Solomon, Izler, 1966 Jan. 18; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 988)
    - Stadelmann, Egon, 1966 Feb. 14; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 989)
      From M. Barolin
    - Sternberg, Daniel, 1951-1980; 9 items. (Box 30, Folder 990)
      Includes a letter from John Weigl
    - Stewart, Miss, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 991)
    - Stokowski, Leopold, [1968?]; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 992)
      Circular letter to "Friends of Music and the American Symphony Orchestra"
    - Stroux, Christoph, 1960-1963; 2 items. (Box 30, Folder 993)
    - Taplin, Frank, 1965 Oct.-Nov.; 2 items. (Box 30, Folder 994)
    - Thanhauser, Justin K., 1966 Apr. 16; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 995)
    - Theodore Presser Co.
      See Bean, Calvert; Hauser, Arthur
    - Tollefsen, Carl, 1950 Feb. 20; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 996)
    - Universal Edition, 1980 Feb. 1; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 997)
    - University of Wyoming. Division of Rare Books and Special Collections, 1978 Mar. 21; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 998)
    - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1967 Sep. 14; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 999)
      To Ira Hirschmann, appended to a letter from him
    - Waldman, Frederic, 1968 Jan. 22; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 1000)
      From Maria Weigl Piers
    - Waldstein, Wilhelm, 1966 Jan. 29; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 1001)
    - Warkow, Stewart J., 1979-1980; 6 items. (Box 30, Folder 1002)
    - Watanabe, Ruth T., 1979-1980; 3 items. (Box 30, Folder 1003)
      One letter from John Weigl
    - Webb, Charles, 1978 Jun. 22; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 1004)
    - Weigl, Etta Ruth Hoskins
    - Weigl, John, 1980, n.d.; 2 items. (Box 30, Folder 1005)
      See also Kapp, Paul; Smyth, Christian; Sternberg, Daniel; Watanabe, Ruth T.; Karl Weigl Correspondence
    - Wiefler, Florian, 1966, n.d.; 3 items. (Box 30, Folder 1006)
    - WNYC (New York), 1964 May 25; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 1007)
    - Yarnall, Elizabeth, 1967 Oct. 14; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 1008)
      To Ira Hirschmann
    - Zelzer, Hugo, 1965 Nov. 10; 1 item. (Box 30, Folder 1009)
    - Unidentified, 1953-1967; 2 items. (Box 30, Folder 1010)
    - Unidentified, n.d.; 1 item. (Box 31, Folder 1046)
  - Karl Weigl Memorial Fund, IX.B
    - Billing statements, 1969-1979, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1011)
    - Contributions, 1967-1972, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1012)
    - Lists of contributors and foundations (Box 30, Folder 1013)
    - Lists of music loaned to musicians, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 1014)
    - Notes, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1015)
    - Recordings, [ca. 1969], n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1016)
  - Other Papers, IX.C
    - Biographical material, typescript and printed, [ca. 1949-1960s], n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1017)
    - Clippings and notes, 1950-1975, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1018)
    - Copyright permission signed by Frances Bragan Richman, 1979 Dec 27 (Box 30, Folder 1019)
    - "Data on the New York Community Trust and Community Funds, Inc.," set of printed pamphlets, [197-?] (Box 30, Folder 1020)
    - "Functional Music With Cerebral Palsied Children," article by Vally Weigl reprinted from Music Therapy, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 1021)
    - Inventories and documents concerning Karl Weigl's papers, 1980-1986, n.d. (Box 30, Folder 1022)
      See also Braunstein, Joseph; Campbell, Frank; Miller, Philip L.; Watanabe, Ruth T.; and John Weigl in Vally Weigl Correspondence
    - List of Christmas gifts given, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 1023)
    - Notes concerning Weigl's death, [1949] (Box 30, Folder 1024)
      See also Castle, William B. in Vally Weigl Correspondence
    - Vally Weigl Performance and Recording Fund, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 1025)
      See also Maves, David in Vally Weigl Correspondence
- Sound Recordings, Series X
  This series consists of performances of Weigl's music recorded after his death. Recordings have been sent to the Yale Collection of Historical Sound Recordings and will be cataloged and stored separately from the rest of the Karl Weigl Papers.